#### CONTACT

mlsaveline@gmail.com

(+44)0 77403 55556

LinkedIn

London, United Kingdom

#### **EDUCATION**

## **MASTER OF ARTS: TELEVISION JOURNALISM**

City University Merit

## **BACHELOR OF ARTS:** INTERNATIONAL RELATIONS AND MUSIC TECHNOLOGY

Keele University 2:1

#### **ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

- Whilst working as a broadcast journalist, brought to light the 'My Heels My Choice' campaign to the global media - a story which went on to change UK employment dress code laws. The story was picked up my multiple news outlets globally and was UK's top news story of the day.
- Whilst at Meta, I played an integral role in increasing product adoption and engagement for a pilot invite-only Facebook program by 160%, that is now known as Meta's Blueprint Certification programme for community management -the world's primary qualification to becoming certified in community management.
- At the BBC, I spearheaded the use of mobile filming for content creation, at a time when this was uncommon e.g. The Mannequin Challenge.

# MIKEY AVELINE

#### **ABOUT**

Digital content strategist with over 8+ years experience, passionate about technology, and experienced working for PaaS, retail, and broadcasting brands. Experienced with leading content and social media strategy for global Tech giants and turning complex topic into compelling content.

Former journalist with an expert editorial and analytical eye, having worked in global newsrooms. I hold a track record of exceeding set expectations.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

















Apr 2018 - Present

### SENIOR CONTENT STRATEGIST (SELF-EMPLOYED) **VARIOUS CLIENTS**

- Leading on editorial content and social media strategy for various agency brand's digital marketing campaigns.
- Project manage content communication between agencies and coach marketing teams.
- Develop content briefs to create storytelling narratives that set creative teams up for success and allow products to resonate with their markets.
- · Identify new influencer talent partnerships, and onboard new creative partners into brand ambassador programs.
- Project manage and ideate innovative marketing campaigns, including launch new social channels and activations
- Oversee copywriting is in line with brand tone, and content research across social media, website blogs, and case studies.
- Coach and present digital marketing courses to small-medium businesses as a consultative product expert.



Jan 2021 - Oct 2021

## **DIGITAL CONTENT MARKETING MANAGER (CONTRACT) AMAZON**

 Led a team of two staff, and managed the content production cycle and defined the social media strategy for Amazon's first TikTok recruitment campaign, from beginning to end in partnership with a creative agency. This promotional campaign exceeded KPIs two-fold and achieved status as a "Top Ad" in TikTok.

#### **TECH SKILLS**

,WordPress, Hubspot,
Salesforce, Hootsuite,
Mailchimp, Facebook
Business, Instagram Business,
Hootsuite, Buffer, Google
Analytics, Mixpanel, Trello,
Asana, Photoshop, Final Cut
Pro, Stripe, Google
Workspace: Sheets, Slides,
Microsoft Office: Word, Excel,
Powerpoint Manager,
Facebook Groups, G Suite,
Slack, GoToWebinar,
Sprinklr.

#### **SKILLS**

- Content strategy
- Strategic planning
- Editorial strategy
- Social media strategy
- Copywriting
- Journalism
- Project management
- Research
- Relationship management
- Partner solutions
- Community management
- Training

## EXTRA-CURRICULAR

#### **PODCAST HOST:**

## NFTeaseMe

Interviewing key Web3 leaders on the latest developments within the metaverse, crypto and NFT sector.

- Creatively problem solved campaign challenges, coordinated brand ambassadors, case studies, analysed data metrics, and provided internal teams with production support and localisation toolkits.
- Managed marketing budget, including paid advertising spend with an external agency.



Jul 2019 - Aug 2020

## COMMUNITY PARTNERSHIPS MANAGER (CONTRACT)

**META** 

- Supported and onboarded creators of the largest and most engaged
   Facebook communities in the world via a partner mentorship academy
   program on community management, while improving upon Facebook's
   products and content through data analysis.
- Launched, content moderated and strategised daily content across 9
   Facebook Groups, while shipping out 20 educational units to over 3000
   managed partners across EMEA, APAC, and LATAM.
- Worked cross-functionally as a liaison between internal and external stakeholders; presenting strategic consultation and analysis on content, analytics, and partner needs to our Data, Product, and Marketing teams.
- Provided customer service support to inbound queries, handled escalations and put out PR statements ensuring a favourable company image.
- Produced webinars, and project managed social editorial calendars alongside newsroom agenda, internal workflow operational processes and content localisation translations.
- Created community management playbook incorporating product knowledge and best practices for engagement and community onboarding experience.



Oct 2015 - Aug 2018

## **BROADCAST & DIGITAL JOURNALIST**

BBC

- Produced, planned, researched, and conceptualised four editorial news stories daily for next-day TV, for BBC London news, within a fastpaced newsroom environment.
- Presented TV packages onscreen for BBC World, and across digital media including at notable events such as The Brit Awards and London Fashion Week.
- Assisted developing innovative TV and digital newsroom content strategies through specialist storytelling techniques to promote engagement and leverage earned media.
- Fostered media contact relations in PR and journalism, and reviewed content licence agreements.
- Briefed internal teams across marketing, legal, public relations, and post production on editorial plans ensuring content is in line with brand tone.